Here's an example of a Python program that uses a DB-API Library to
这里是一个 Python 程序使用 DB-API 库来访问数据库
query a database.
的一个例子
Everytime you use DB-API from your code,
当你每次在代码中使用 DB-API 的时候
you're going to have the following steps.
你都要按照下面的步骤来
First, we have import sqlite3, that's the library for
首先导入 sqlite3  这个库所针对的
the database we're using.
就是我们使用的数据库
If we were using postgreSQL here, we would import psyco-pg instead.
但如果我们使用的是 postgreSQL 的话 就要导入 psyco-pg 了
Next, connect to the database.
接下来 连接数据库
The string cookies here, is the name of the database to connect to.
这里的字符串 cookies 就是要连接数据库的名字
Yes, there's a reason I've put the name cookies in this example.
我在这里把它叫做 cookies 是有原因的
I'll tell you at the end of the video, I promise.
视频结束的时候我会告诉你的 我保证
If you were using a database system over a network, instead you might have to
如果通过网络来使用数据库 你就必须要
specify the host name, username, password and other information here.
在这里指定主机名称 用户名 密码 还有其他的信息
The connect function returns a connection object,
连接函数返回一个连接对象
which is good until you close that connection.
在你断开连接之前都能用
Next, your code will make an object called a cursor.
接下来 你的代码就会产生出一个叫做光标的对象
The cursor is what actually runs queries and fetches results.
这个光标就会去运行查询语句并获得结果
It's called a cursor because when the database gives you results.
之所以叫它光标 是因为当数据库给你结果时
You use the cursor to scan through the results,
你会用光标来观测这些结果
kind of like a text cursor in an editor.
就像文字编辑器里的光标一样
You can see here that we execute a query using a cursor, and
你看 我们执行一条查询语句用到了光标
then fetch all the results from that query also using the cursor.
接着从查询语句中获取结果也要用到光标
Another possibility is to fetch the results one at a time using
还有一种情况是 每次只获取一个结果
the fetchone method on cursors.
使用光标的 fetchone 方法
Now, if you were doing an insert query instead of a select,
好 如果你发出一条 insert 命令而不是 select
you'd need to commit the insertion here, or if something went wrong, roll back.
你就要在这提交（commit）这次的插入 否则如果发生了错误 就回滚（roll back）至原状态
Same if you were doing some other query that changes the database.
对于其他的改变数据库的命令也是一样的
Commit and roll back are methods on connection.
提交（commit）和 回滚（roll back）是连接的方法
In this case, we're doing a select, so we don't need to.
这个情况 我们做的是一个 select 所以就不用了
I'll tell you more about commits and
我会在后面深入讲解提交（commit）和回滚（roll back）的
roll backs a little later, along with doing inserts and DBAPI.
并且还会说一下插入和 DB-API
Finally, when you're done, you close the connection.
最后 完成任务后 你要关闭连接
It's important to always close connections when we're done with them,
每次完成后都关闭连接是非常重要的
especially if this code were running inside of a loop.
特别是当这段代码还运行在循环体中时
We wouldn't want to have a bunch of stale connections sitting around,
谁都不想让一大堆废弃的连接占用
taking up resources.
大量资源
By the way, I mentioned that cookies here isn't just to be silly.
对了 我前面提到了 cookies 并不是瞎编搞笑的
If you were to run this exact code against the cookies file from a Chrome
如果你对 Chrome 浏览器的 cookies 文件运行这些代码
web browser, it would tell you some of the web servers you have cookies from.
你就能得到一些有 cookies 记录的 Web 服务信息
Both Chrome and
这是因为 Chrome
Firefox use an SQLite database to store cookies and web history.
和 Firefox 都使用 SQLite 数据库来存储 cookies 和历史记录